LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
I'm a soldier - that means I'm
Both a defendant and the judge
I am standing on both ends of the flame
Rounding curves
Overtaking life and death,
I run and fight with false shadows
No matter how many threads of
deception are woven together,
The truth shall illuminate the face of light
Save your tears for the day
when our pain is far behind
on your feet, come with me
We are soldiers stand or die
Save your fears, take your place
Save them for the judgement day
fast and free, follow me
Time to make the sacrifice.
We rise or fall
Hey, look!
There was a classified file on the
Individual Eleven in the police's array!
Really? Let me see! Let me see!
That's intriguing!
What, what?
I want to see, too!
Where, where?
Here, this.
Good job finding it!
I want to see, too...
Now, now... You mustn't go diving into
a place like that without permission.
It's impossible to stop their curiosity.
We just have to delete any
dangerous data they pick up.
Hardware maintenance comes first.
You're too soft on them, sir...
getting bought out by presents like that.
So the one wearing red clothes... likes Akafuku.
Tachikoma is making a pun about
red clothes akai fuku and the sweets Akafuku
And, the one who has the sweet tooth...
is too soft.
Tachikoma is making a pun about having a
sweet tooth amatou and being too soft amasugi
That wasn't funny at all.
Afternoon
of the
Machines
Well, well. You guys are having a party, huh?
Oh, Batou-San!
Are you guys acting up again?
Oh please, Togusa-kun, give us more credit.
We were trying to conduct our own
investigation of the Individual Eleven.
Even though Bomer-kun collected
a specimen of the virus,
we can't make a vaccine because we haven't been
able to specify the activation factor, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Well yeah, that's the case.
Right, right?
So we tried looking into police data.
Please take a look.
The eleven who killed themselves seem to
share similarities in their lines of work.
They are former SDF officers,
former police officers,
and mercenaries.
Also, we should not overlook the
fact that all of them had cybernetic
implants that accounted for more
than fifty percent of their bodies.
Besides, isn't it said that there are more than
twenty thousand known carriers of the virus?
if we don't make a vaccine as soon as possible, there may
be more victims like the journalist Togusa-kun encountered.
That's not your job.
But...
We've asked Spring-8 to investigate
the Individual Eleven's deaths.
So... we're about to go there to
meet up with the Major, and...
she asked us to bring one of you along.
Batou-San!
I wanna go!
Well, we can't take anyone
if you all need maintenance.
Me, me, me!
I'm done with maintenance!
Oh, you?
All right, let's go.
Roger!
So it's your personal Tachikoma in the end.
Uh...
Hey!
Please wait for me!
Hey, that's not fair!
Why, why, why?
Why just him?
Whaaa?
What's going on...?
Why did he get to go?
It's decided already?
I'm so jealous.
Sooo jealous...
I haven't put the oil in yet...
That's so mean...
It's so not fair!
Geez, what's up with that? It's always him.
It's always him!
It's strange.
Even though none of us have used natural
oil since switching to these bodies,
why is it that he's still
Batou's personal favourite?
Yeah... it feels like we're individualising
at an even greater rate than before, too.
Why'd you think that is, Proto-kun?
Who knows? I wonder.
Maybe it's because we set up that server
and reprogrammed it to permit the data
of individual units to remain separate.
You guys quiet down already.
We'll never get done.
We can talk here without interruptions.
Yeah, we don't have to worry about time, either!
Getting back to the original topic,
putting aside the Individual
Eleven, who were infected by the virus,
what do you guys think of
particularists in general?
Don't you think they rather lack individuality,
despite their emphasis on individualism?
That's true.
I mean, even though they seek
worth through individual merit
in their pursuit for isolation on the net,
in addition to prove that their ego
exists, they're united in their
attempts to eradicate everyone who
has a different opinion, right?
Yeah!
The group seemingly has identity, but doesn't.
I feel they are people who've fallen into a state of
non-identity as a result of their wanting to have one too much.
In a way, I feel as though
they are antithetical to us.
That's right.
I mean, we're obliged to
synchronise with each other,
but we managed to develop egos in the past.
And now that they're respecting
our differences as individualism,
we only need to synchronise necessary data.
Oh?
Then, supposing the particularists
are ending up as a homogenous group
because they want to be individualistic,
who determines their will as a group entity?
For the Individual Eleven,
I'd say it was Gouda from the
Cabinet Intelligence Agency.
But the terrorists who attacked the Chinese Embassy
are thought to be individualists who took action
without any connection to the virus, right?
There are sociologists who say their origins go back to
the mimics that emerged in the Laughing Man case, too.
Then that means that the
particularists shared a vision
that closely reflected the current situation
before Gouda's plan began to intervene.
As in the eradication of refugees
as the consensus of the people.
Well, if you're going to put it that way,
the refugees repeatedly engaged in terrorist activities
before the Individual Eleven emerged, right?
Isn't it strange?
Even though no one in
particular is issuing commands,
things are mysteriously beginning
to turn towards the same direction.
It could be that there is a third
decision-making body for humans,
aside from the individual and the group.
What do you mean?
For instance, there is Dawkins, who
sought it on a microscopic level in DNA,
and Lovelock, who sought it on a
very macroscopic level in Earth.
Biosphere!
The two of them have left behind works
that, while having two opposing subjects,
arrive at what could be construed as an
identical conclusion around the same time.
This. This, this, this.
What kind of things are written in there?
Humans are the smallest unit capable
of rational thought and initiative.
They think and allude to holon-structured entities that are
larger and smaller than themselves, or something like that.
Note: A holon is something that is both a discrete
individual as well as a part of a larger whole
In other words,
it seems to refer to the possibility that the causative
factor for the actions of both particularists and refugees
lies on a more microscopic
level than they do themselves,
or a more macroscopic level
than they do as a group.
That's so hard to understand!
It's easy!
The network's current state did not really
exist before human affirmed its existence.
Along with the human neural
network and the electronic network,
its condition loosely structures
the human subconscious,
which deviated from the human consciousness,
as the collective consciousness.
Right?
In other words,
the human mind is no longer
congruous with the body,
but humans haven't realised this?
Yeah, that'd be my blunt opinion.
I was just leaning towards the conclusion that
the body and the mind are inseparable, too!
What a change!
Assuming it's true,
then it means Gouda intentionally
created a medium that would
accelerate the process!
Hey!
I'm done.
Take my place already.
Sorry, sorry.
Our debate got pretty heated.
Let me synchronise with the debate subject.
Okay!
I see.
That's interesting.
Isn't it
But I also feel lately that my consciousness
isn't congruous with my body.
What do you mean?
I guess it feels like there is another
you high up above, looking down at you.
Oh yeah, I feel that too!
Is our identity located in each of our bodies,
or is it shared between us Tachikoma as a group?
Well, it'd be the latter,
considering that synchronisation
is the underlying assumption
of our basic program.
After all, the Major, who is our
God, is also a mediating factor.
But even though the use of natural oil has been
prohibited, our individualisation continues to progress.
We're supposed to be completely
homogenised, but we're individualised and,
in addition, subconsciously experiencing the divergence
between our physical bodies and information.
Could it be...
Could it be?
Th...
Well, wait.
We must not rush to conclusions.
Isn't that just a disengagement we feel
from having the agent function added?
That may be true,
but I can't help but feel that there is another identity
somewhere, aside from the physical body and the mind!
I totally understand.
Before, when I fought with the Jigabachi,
I was instantaneously able to act as the Major's
shield without experiencing any fear of death.
There was a certain sense that I decided
somewhere that my body wasn't just my own.
Was that different from that indescribable euphoria
we felt when we knew we wanted to save Batou-San?
Yeah, it was different.
It was a more visceral response that
felt more programmed than anything else.
If that's the case,
then the third identity you sensed
may unfortunately be different
from what it would be for humans.
Besides, we weren't even told where the server that
holds our shared information is located, right?
That server could be what the third identity is.
So it was an illusion that we obtained ghosts.
It may be necessary for us to think more
in-depth about the third identity you felt.
Let me synchronise with that feeling!
Sure.
Any possibility that these results are wrong?
None.
We found dissolved fragments of
the proteins which constituted
the micro machines that were
in the pilot's bloodstream.
We could not extract specific information from the
cyberbrains of the so-called Individual Eleven, however.
I knew what results would be,
but I wanted to make certain.
The results on the pilot are a gain, though.
So this means the pilot was
murdered using micro machines, huh?
We can't rule out the possibility
that he took some himself.
It would've been perfect
if there was evidence that the appearance of the eleven
helicopters was a trigger in some way from the body's cyberbrain.
I guess we couldn't be that optimistic.
What about the gunpowder?
A molecular analysis says it's the same type of
explosive as the C-4 made on the Peninsula.
Lately, the substance has also been
frequently found in confiscated material
that enters Japan via Taiwan.
What's that?
Tachikoma, can you see anything?
There seems to have been an explosion!
There have been a lot of terrorism-related
requests for investigations lately, so...
I'm guessing we were targeted.
Hey, what happened?
Describe the situation as well as you can.
Yes, sir.
It seems something exploded, but...
Yes, there are sectors that deal
with flammable substances, but...
Even so, I don't see anyone running out.
Yes, that's right.
Is this place abandoned?
Actually, a few days ago there were threats
that some explosives would be set off here,
so we were on alert, but...
I guess it could've been a lot worse.
But there's a chance that Doctor Asuda,
the principal investigator,
was here for the afternoon.
Why didn't you say so before?!
Major, we're at the site of the explosion.
From what I can tell,
it's about the same as a gas explosion.
Any victims?
A researcher called Asuda was supposedly
here, but we're still checking.
Asuda..?
Tachikoma, what's the data on that researcher?
He seems to be the one we're looking for, but...
Umm...
Hm? What is it?
Well, I've seen this man somewhere.
Maybe you met him when you had structural analysis.
I thought so too, but there is no
corresponding record in my memory.
HQ, search the IR system for
both Itami and Niihama airports,
as wells as the roads that have access to them,
to see if there is a record of someone
who matches Doctor Asuda's profile.
Understood.
Major, what's going on?
The explanation can wait.
Let the authorities handle it and return to the Tilt.
He's probably headed to Niihama Airport.
Hey everyone!
What is it, all of a sudden?
Please check if there are any
records that match this individual.
I can't shake off the feeling that
I've met him somewhere before.
Umm...
Who was he?
I know I've seen him before,
but my memory doesn't have any data on him, either.
But that means you've never seen him before, right?
You guys, cut it out!
I can almost remember, but I can't!
The synapses just aren't connecting.
"Synapses"?
Don't use such an organic analogy!
Hey, don't you feel that it's as though
there's a partition in our cyberbrain with this memory,
but that we're being barred from accessing it?
Yeah, yeah!
Dr. Asuda is the researcher
who single-handedly developed
the prototype of the Tachikoma's neurochip.
So he's the Tachikoma's "parent"?
You could put it that way, yes.
Dr. Asuda helped us personally
when we rebuilt the Tachikomas.
He's the reason we were able to devise
a method to preserve their experiences
by adding the agent function and
creating a dual-structure memory.
And that doctor is involved with this explosion?
He was probably the one who did it.
His reason being?
To seek asylum with the results of his research.
The professor prided himself on
having invented the neurochip.
However, his status was that of
a government research scientist.
While he invented an AI ahead of its time,
he himself could not get the patent.
With that in mind, we had arranged it so
that he could conduct a structural analysis
of the Tachikomas' current situation
and the neurochip's developmental progress.
So that's why you told us to bring
along one of the Tachikoma units...
Then why do we have vague memories of him?
Well, we erased your memories of
each structural analysis session,
but the professor probably thought he wanted to
leave a record of his achievements somewhere,
and wrote himself into a part of your memory.
Major.
We have found Dr. Asuda in
the Niihama Airport lobby.
All right.
Keep him under surveillance.
Chief.
I delayed all the flights
leaving for North America.
Thanks.
Thank you, Prime Minister Kayabuki.
There is no need to thank me.
We were able to prevent one of our preeminent
minds and his AI research
from leaving the country.
It is thanks to my subordinates' efforts.
To all travellers:
all flights to North America have
been delayed due to inclement weather.
So that's what it was.
But I still can't remember this professor.
I guess the synapses aren't connecting.
Didn't you say that you don't like that expression?
I know!
Hey, Proto-kun.
We're going to open up his brain, okay?
What?
What is this about all of a sudden?
Are you saying that synchronisation isn't
enough and that you now want even my AI?
Nah.
I just want to check where he
made the partition in the AI.
You idiot! Don't do things without permission!
What? What's wrong?
Nothing! It's not there!
His AI!
Could it be that we're all... brainless?!
Then...
Where are our AIs?
You are Dr. Asuda, correct?
You have violated the Arms Export Restriction Law.
Come with me, please.
I refuse.
I will work in a country where
my rights are recognised.
You became a government research scientist in
return for facilities and funding, didn't you?
You should be the first one to
realise that you can't do that.
I'm disappointed.
I brought this Tachikoma to the lab to see you.
I see.
Um...
Are you my...
father?
"Father", eh?
Right now, they are stable, but who knows when
something will make them go haywire again.
Would you like to tell us how to erase the memory
that you presumably wrote in without permission?
Once upon a time,
a nameless carpenter who built a castle
deliberately left behind the tools
that he used to carve his name
in the attic beams as proof that he was
involved in the castle's construction.
Would you erase even that
small trace of my sentiments?
Yes.
That is the fate of those who have surrendered
to the system in order to gain power.
Delete the C9 file that I built at your request into
that satellite's cyberbrain hub's eighth sector.
Understood.
Major, what's this satellite about?
I get it!
The reason why we felt that
our identity was "elsewhere"
was because our AIs were synchronising via
the cyberbrain hub on that satellite, right?
That's right.
Then that means the server's
on that satellite, too!
So we were perceiving the satellite's super
bird's-eye vantage as our third identity?
So until now, we didn't notice
the route our consciousness took
because our AIs don't have sensory perception!
So that's why the unity between our
program and our bodies became unnecessary!
I can now understand why I didn't fear death!
But in any case...
to think that it's up in space...
How awe-inspiring...
But... I feel that...
I don't want your memory erased...
Don't fret over it.
My ideology towards the AI that I
envisioned will remain somewhere on the net.
Major.
What's going to happen to him?
Since we got him,
allowances may be possible to some degree.
If he's lucky, he'll be sentenced to prison.
And if he's unlucky?
He may end up spending the rest of his life cooped
up in the Harima laboratory, conducting research.
We should take the Tachikomas
to visit him now and then.
I wonder.
Like us, there is no longer freedom for him
after having sought it.
Finding out a galaxy
of planets and stars within me.
Listening to each of them
singing the same silent melody.
I've never seen such beauty
in possibility...
No smack of doubt or fear.
(Wake up)
I hear a voice.
(And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside (Our time is now)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth) All I need,
to make all this reality.
(it's inside)
The beauty within the shell.
(deep within the shell)
(within the shell)
(Wake up)
I hear a voice (And show the light)
hear a voice calling out to me.
(Wake up)
I see inside, (the time is now)
see the light now ever holding me.
All the truth,
(All the truth) All I need,
to make all this reality,
it's inside
right here within this shell.